<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Beneath the Piled Centuries</title>
    <link>http://januzellij.github.io/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Beneath the Piled Centuries</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 10:32:12 -0500</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://januzellij.github.io/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Some Objections to Utilitarianism</title>
      <link>http://januzellij.github.io/posts/objections-to-utilitarianism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Sep 2022 10:32:12 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://januzellij.github.io/posts/objections-to-utilitarianism/</guid>
      <description>I want to go over some objections I have with utilitarianism. Partially this is for my own selfish benefit so I can stop thinking about this all the time, but it’s also because most laymen/naive objections to utilitarianism that I’ve encountered are very weak (some examples here). This weakness comes from the fact that the way utilitarianism is presented is ingenious, to the point that is seems like the correct ethical system ipso facto; a paragon of rationality floating far above the teeming, grimy hoards of common folk.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Travis Scott and Consequentialism</title>
      <link>http://januzellij.github.io/posts/travis-scott-consequentialism/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 16:23:38 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://januzellij.github.io/posts/travis-scott-consequentialism/</guid>
      <description>Consequentialism has no good way of handling multi-causal events, and correctly assigning moral blame/praise to the events.
Example: Suppose I give $.01 to a pedophile. Is this moral or immoral consequentially? I am giving money to a pedophile, which makes it easier for them buy child pornography. However, $.01 by itself cannot buy anything. In a vacuum, this is a morally blameless act: the pedophile cannot do anything with x + .</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>What is a Probability</title>
      <link>http://januzellij.github.io/posts/what-is-a-probability/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Jan 2022 16:19:32 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://januzellij.github.io/posts/what-is-a-probability/</guid>
      <description>What is a probability? The junkyard cyclone.
There’s a popular saying concerning the chance that abiogenesis could come about without the assistance of a Divine creator: “comparable to the chance that a tornado sweeping through a junkyard might assemble a Boeing 747”. There are plenty of biological objections to this, but I want to use it as an example to talk about probabilities: what they are and what they can tell you.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Why facts suck and don&#39;t matter</title>
      <link>http://januzellij.github.io/posts/facts-suck-and-dont-matter/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2020 15:14:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://januzellij.github.io/posts/facts-suck-and-dont-matter/</guid>
      <description>These days people talk an awful lot about facts: mainly how the out-group has the facts wrong and if they&amp;rsquo;d only get past their feelings we&amp;rsquo;d all be on the same page. The problem is, facts as they exist today are absolutely awful. We expect them to do far more rhetorical work than they&amp;rsquo;re capable of.
A big problem is that the word &amp;ldquo;fact&amp;rdquo; is a stand in for a lot of different kinds of knowledge.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Difficulties Motivating Mathematics</title>
      <link>http://januzellij.github.io/posts/difficulties-motivating-mathematics/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Aug 2018 20:15:00 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://januzellij.github.io/posts/difficulties-motivating-mathematics/</guid>
      <description>K-12 math education has major issues. Teaching is extremely formulaic, little time is spent on proofs of basic results, and creativity is rarely encouraged. But this is a solvable problem, since the barriers to fixing these problems are bureaucratic: we know how to teach math well, it&amp;rsquo;s getting people to do it widespread at the K-12 level that&amp;rsquo;s difficult.
I’d like to instead talk about a difficulty that arises when motivating math at a higher level (graduate level or research level).</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
